烧死他们
Burn them all!
我妹妹在哪里
Where's my sister?
烧死他们
Burn them all!
求求你
Please.
烧死他们
Burn them. Burn them all!
Burn them all!
梅拉
Meera.
他们发现我们了
They found us.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
跟我来  快
Come with me, now.
死人是不会停步的
The dead don't rest.
真绿
It's so green.
是啊
Oh, yes.
一到河间地以南
Once you get south of the Riverlands,
地上的树种类就多起来了
very different sorts of trees start to take over.
枫树  榆树  山毛榉  白杨
Maple, elm, beech, poplar.
柳树
The odd willow.
不过现在夏天已经过去
And of course now that summer's over,
你会看到一些秋天的颜色加进来
you'll start seeing the autumn colors coming in.
但是你在这边能见到的绿色仍然比别处都多
Still, you'll find more green here than anywhere else.
你紧张了  你一紧张就不停说话
You're nervous. You're a nervous talker.
一点儿也不比一紧张就说不出话好
That's not any better being a nervous mute.
我还以为再也回不来了
I didn't think I'd ever come back here
当初离开前父亲逼我放弃封号和继承权
after my father made me renounce my title and inheritance
还威胁说不合作就杀掉我
and, well, threaten to kill me if I didn't.
那种时候凭谁也知道这个家不要我了
A person just doesn't feel welcome at that point.
更没想过有天会带妻儿来见他
And I certainly didn't expect to be introducing him to my family.
你知道见了他们怎么说吧
So you know what to tell them.
说小山姆是你的孩子
That Little Sam is your baby.
是的  这非常重要
Yes, now that's very important.
让他认为小山姆是他孙子
If he thinks that Little Sam is his grandchild,
他就会接纳你们
he'll take you in.
小山姆会有人教  读书识字
He'll get an education. He'll learn to read.
你也能帮忙教他
And you can help teach him. Huh?
你怎么跟家里人讲我的
What did you tell your family about me?
我跟他们说  在北境遇见的你
I told them I met you in the North.
你讲了是多北的北边吗
Did you tell them how far north?
写信的纸没那么大张啦
Well, it wasn't a very large piece of parchment.
你没告诉他们我的真实来历
You didn't tell them where I'm really from?
没告诉他们我是野人
You didn't tell them I'm a wildling?
问题是
The thing is...
我父亲不喜欢野人
my father doesn't like wildlings.
他希望我能成为男子汉
He hoped I'd make a man of myself by
去"杀几个该死的野人"
"Killing some bloody wildlings,"
所以如果可能的话  最好不要提这事
so it's probably a good subject to avoid if at all possible.
我想我们到了
I think we're here.
山姆
Sam.
Oh, Sam.
您好  母亲
Oh, hello, Mother.
我还以为再也见不到你了
I never thought I'd see you again.
你气色不错
You look wonderful.
塔拉
Talla?
诸神啊  你长成大姑娘了
Gods, you're a woman now.
父亲要我嫁给西蒙·佛索威
Father says I have to marry Symun Fossoway.
-他一口黄牙...  -够了  塔拉
- He has yellow teeth-- - That's enough, Talla.
母亲  这是吉莉
Oh, um, Mother, this is Gilly.
天哪
Oh, my.
你真漂亮
You are lovely.
很高兴认识您  塔利夫人
I am happy to know you, Lady Tarly.
还有这个
Oh, and this,
是我们的儿子山姆威尔
this is our son Samwell.
你好啊  小家伙
Hello, little one.
我是你的祖母
It's me, your grandmother.
可以抱抱他吗
May I hold him?
当然了
Yes, of course.
一看就是个鬼机灵
You have a curious mind, I can tell.
跟你爸爸一样  长大了要当学士
You'll be a scholar like your father.
父亲去哪儿了  狄肯呢
Where is Father? And Dickon?
他们去打猎了
They're on a hunt.
晚饭时候回来
They'll join us for dinner.
进来吧  这么远的路
Come inside. Such a journey.
一定累坏了
You must be exhausted.
来吧  颠簸一路你一定想洗澡
Come, you'll be wanting a bath after all that travel.
还要换一件正餐穿的裙子
Oh, and a dress for dinner.
你可以穿我的
You can wear one of mine.
你喜欢什么颜色
What's your color?
午夜蓝还是银色
Midnight blue or silver?
或许银色  快来
Silver, maybe. Come.
你愿意话可以在我的房间里选一间住
You can choose one of my bedrooms if you want.
没有别的办法吗
Is there no other way?
你怕她有危险
You're afraid for her?
我当然怕
Of course I'm afraid for her!
看起来就很危险
It just seems very dangerous.
她会受到保护的
She'll be protected the entire way.
战士之子对越界之人
The Faith Militant are very stern
绝不容情
with those who overstep their bounds.
况且玛格丽王后不是你母亲
And Queen Margaery isn't your mother.
我想诸神也会为她
I suspect the gods will predispose the common people
让平民温和起来
to gentleness on her behalf.
她真正对他们敞开过心扉
She's truly opened her heart to them.
她一直都热衷帮助穷苦和不幸的平民
She's always been very devoted to the poor and the unfortunate.
对七神也诚心信奉
And now she's devoted to the gods as well.
你想见她吗
Would you like to see her?
他们有伤害你吗
Have they hurt you?
他们有对你不好吗
Have they mistreated you?
-没有  陛下  -我好想你
- No, Your Grace. - I've missed you.
你都不知道我多想你
More than you could know.
我们很快就能团聚了
We'll be together again soon
一切都会比从前好
and everything will be better than it was before.
怎么会好
Better how?
很快就有...
Soon the--
赎罪之旅
walk of atonement.
他说没有别的办法
He says there's no other way.
你跟大麻雀谈过吗
Have you spoken to him at all, the High Sparrow?
是的  谈过几次
Yes, a few times.
你呢
Have you?
谈过
Yes, I have.
他跟我们想的不太一样  是吧
He's not quite what we thought he was, is he?
你觉得我疯了
You think I'm mad.
我听上去像是疯了
I sound mad.
不  没有
No. No, you don't.
你绝不会的
You-- you could never.
你说得对  他是跟我们想的不一样
You're right, he's not.
他要更...
He's a lot more--
是的
He is.
他很特别
There's something about him.
他看待这世界的方式
His way of looking at the world.
承认真实的自己并不容易
It's not an easy thing admitting to yourself what you really are.
我花了好久才肯面对
It's taken me a while.
他帮助了我
He's helped me.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你是个好人  你一直是个好人
You're a good person. You've always been a good person.
你是我认识的最好的人
You're the best person I know.
我刚刚还跟他谈起你对穷人的奉献
I was just telling him about your devotion to the poor.
是啊  我去他们的茅舍
Ah, yes, I visited their hovels
我给他们汤喝  而且确保让人看到
and I fed them soup and I made sure I was seen doing it.
但他们真正需要的我没有给他们
I never gave them what they really needed, though.
我有很多时间去思考我多么擅长假仁假义
I've had lots of time to think about how good I was at seeming good.
我对自己的本质  行善的动机
All those stories I told myself about who I was
充满了自欺欺人的想法
and why I did the things I did.
其中有太多谎言
There were so many lies in those stories.
我不懂
I don't understand.
没关系  真的
It's all right. It really is.
放下那些谎言让我如释重负
It's such a relief to let go of those lies.
那洛拉斯呢
What about Loras?
我爱我哥哥
I love my brother.
我会永远爱我哥哥
I will always love my brother.
他的灵魂是纯粹而完美的
His soul is pure and perfect.
他的罪孽并不能抹去那份纯洁
His sins don't erase that purity,
只是遮掩了它
they only obscure it.
他只需要赎罪
He just needs to atone for them.
我们都得赎罪
We all do.
不论如何  或迟或早
Sooner or later, one way or another.
诸神对我们所有人都有计划
The gods have a plan for us all.
穿这个走路真不舒服
It's hard to walk in this.
真美
It's beautiful.
你真美
You're beautiful.
这鹿肉  很好吃
This venison, it's very tasty.
是今天打来的吗
Is it from today's hunt?
不是
Well, no.
那只还没处理完呢
We haven't been able to cure that one yet.
这只是上周的
This is last week's.
当然了  抱歉
Oh, of course. Sorry.
路途劳顿
Long journey.
在七十码开外射倒了它
Brought it down from 70 yards.
一击致命
One shot.
好远啊
Oh, that's a fair distance.
你在长城也常打猎吗
So do you do much hunting up at the Wall?
是的  当然
Oh, yes. Yes.
常打呢
A good amount.
在长城以北
North of the Wall,
不打猎就没得吃
you don't hunt, you don't eat.
一般是猎鹿还是跟我们一样猎麋鹿
Mostly deer or is it elk as well?
兔子
Rabbits.
有时候猎松鼠
Sometimes squirrels.
"我们"主要是指我朋友琼恩
I say "We," It's my friend Jon mostly.
有时还有艾迪
Sometimes Edd.
还有吉莉
Oh, and Gilly.
她也是个好猎手
She's-- she's quite a good hunter as well.
女猎手
Um, huntress.
这在你们那里是常事吧
I imagine it's common where you're from.
我们遇到过一个人
We once met a man,
最后壁炉城的安柏大人  对吧  蓝道
Lord Umber from Last Hearth, wasn't it, Randyll,
说他的女儿都要学打猎
who said he taught all his daughters how to hunt.
你父亲教你打猎吗
Your father taught you to hunt?
我们的父亲是绝不会教我们的
Our father would never teach us.
我们的父亲大概能跟你父亲学学
I think our father could learn a thing or two from your father.
够了
That's enough of that.
山姆威尔  你还想再来点面包吗
Samwell, would you care for more bread?
好  当然
Yes. Yes, please.
谢谢  妈妈
Thank you, Mother.
还不够胖吗
Not fat enough already?
我是依总司令的命令南下
I travelled south under orders from the Lord Commander.
-他要我...  -我读过你的信
- He wants me to-- - I read your letter.
你要做个学士
You're to be a maester.
是的  等我拿到了项链
Yes. And once I have my chain,
我就回黑城堡
I'll return to Castle Black.
我以为守夜人能让你历练成男人
I thought the Night's Watch might make a man of you.
至少有点男人样
Something resembling a man at least.
你还是那么软弱  肥胖
You managed to stay soft and fat.
埋头读书
Your nose buried in books.
终生读着比你强的人的成就
Spending your life reading about the achievements of better men.
我敢说你至今都不会骑马挥剑
I'll wager you still can't sit a horse or wield a sword.
蓝道  做守夜人的学士是无上的荣耀
Randyll, to be maester of the Night's Watch is a great honor.
他会挥剑
He can wield a sword.
他杀了一个瑟恩人
He killed a Thenn.
他杀了一个异鬼
He killed a white walker.
那根本不存在
There's no such thing.
我们南下去黑城堡的路上我亲眼所见
I saw it with my own eyes on our way down to Castle Black.
他用一把匕首刺中了异鬼的心脏
He drove a dagger into the walker's heart.
他不止一次为救我冒生命危险
He risked his own life to save mine more than once.
他是你俩永远比不上的伟大勇士
He's a greater warrior than either of you will ever be.
你们南下去黑城堡的路上
Your way down to Castle Black?
你在哪儿杀的异鬼
Where did he kill a white walker?
你从哪儿来
Where are you from?
你怎么遇见我儿子的
How'd you come to meet my son?
守夜人来了我们的堡垒
The Night's Watch came to our keep.
-在哪里  -吉莉
- Where? - Gilly.
-长城以北  -长城以北
- North of the Wall. - North of the Wall?
你是野人
You're a wildling.
七国对这些野蛮人
The Seven Kingdoms have waged war
宣战数百年
against these savages for centuries
我却在自家大厅里招待了一个
and here I sit hosting one in my hall
多亏了我儿子
thanks to my son.
看见那柄剑了吗
See that sword?
它叫碎心
It's called Heartsbane.
在我们家族传承了五百年
It's been in our family for 500 years.
它是一把瓦雷利亚钢剑
It's Valyrian steel.
世上屈指可数
Only a handful of them left in the world.
本该在我死后  传给我的长子
It's supposed to go to my firstborn son after I die.
传给他
To him.
他永远用不了那剑
He will never wield that sword.
他要是成为角陵伯爵
If he were to become Lord Tarly of Horn Hill,
这个家族就完了
it would be the end of this house.
我见到你时  以为你是鼹鼠村的婊子
I took you for a Mole's Town whore when I saw you
这我可以接受
and I made my peace with that.
还有谁会跟着他呢
Who else would have him?
但我高估了他
But I overestimated him.
不
No.
引诱我儿子的是个野人婊子
It was a wildling whore that seduced my son.
你是在报复我吗  儿子
This you getting back at me, boy?
把她带回家  让我跟她同桌吃饭
Bringing that to my table and making me dine with it?
你得到你想要的了  不是吗
And you got what you were after, didn't you?
一个野种  一个混血野种
A bastard. A half-breed bastard.
让你成为我们家的一员
Your invitation into our home.
走吧  亲爱的  塔拉
Come, my dear. Talla.
我没胃口了
I've lost my appetite.
他让家族蒙羞
He dishonors us.
你让你自己蒙羞
You dishonor yourself.
你母亲是个好人  你配不上她
Your mother's a fine woman. You're not worthy of her.
为了哄她开心  我会接纳野人
To please her, I'll take the wildling in.
她可以在厨房干活
She can work in the kitchens.
你的野种交给家里抚养
The bastard will be raised here.
但这是你在角陵待的最后一夜
But this will be the last night you ever spend at Horn Hill.
抱歉  我放任他那样对待你
I'm sorry I let him treat you that way.
我担心他不肯接纳你和小山姆
I was afraid he'd turn you and Little Sam away.
我不生你的气
I'm not angry at you.
我生气的是
I'm angry that horrible people
坏人那样对待好人  却不遭报应
can treat good people that way and get away with it.
你什么时候出发
When do you have to go?
天亮就走
First light.
代我跟他道别
Say good-bye to him for me.
你不是他说的那种人  山姆
You're not what he thinks you are, Sam.
他不知道你是什么样的人
He doesn't know what you are.
再见  吉莉
Good-bye, Gilly.
-山姆  -我们走
- Sam? - We're leaving.
-什么  -收拾行李
- What? - Get your things.
我没有行李
I don't have any things.
-你在做什么  -我们应该在一起
- What are you doing? - We belong together.
我们仨
All of us.
你母亲和妹妹怎么办
What about your mother and sister?
她们会理解的
Oh, they'll understand.
你妹妹的裙子
Your sister's dress.
她不会在意的
She won't mind.
反正你穿着也比她好看
Looks better on you anyway.
山姆
Sam.
那是你父亲的剑
That's your father's sword.
是我家族的剑
It's my family's sword.
山姆
Sam.
他不会想要夺回去吗
Won't he come for it?
他大可一试
He can bloody well try.
狮子和玫瑰喜结良缘
The lion and the rose are one.
感谢天上诸神
I thank the gods above.
对你  我美丽的新娘
And to you, my beauteous bride,
我许诺永恒的爱
I pledge undying love.
乔佛里国王万岁  玛格丽王后万岁
Hail King Joffrey. Hail Queen Margaery.
我要敬我的新王后一杯
I'll drink a toast to my new queen,
没有比她更美的女人
for there is no one fairer.
亲爱的舅舅  你愿意分享我的喜悦
Dear Uncle, will you share my joy
为我斟酒吗
and be my royal cupbearer?
多喝一点甜酒
Drink long and deep, my noble king,
我高贵的国王
from this cup of sweet wine.
这会是他喝的最后一杯酒
The last drink he shall ever take.
这是我的复仇
And vengeance shall be mine.
有毒
Poison!
谋杀
Murder!
我气喘吁吁  我死期将近
I gasp. I-- I die.
我踉踉跄跄
I limp.
是他
And it was he...
毒死了我
that poisoned me.
我恶毒的舅舅小恶魔
My evil Uncle Imp.
我的长子
My firstborn son.
我的黄金狮子
My golden lion
被卑鄙错误地杀死
foully, falsely slain.
愿你能够安息
I pray you found a lasting peace
免受冲突和痛苦
free from strife and pain.
听听我的祈祷  残忍的诸神
Hear my prayer, Oh cruel gods.
让我替他去死
Take my life instead.
我亲爱的儿子死了  我也活不下去
For I cannot face another day when my sweet boy is dead.
悲伤
Oh, woe.
痛苦
Oh, grief.
最黑暗的日子  我的心充满哀痛
Oh, darkest day, my heart is full of sorrow.
希望通通破灭
All hope is lost.
快乐烟消云散
All joy is gone.
明天也不复存在
And there is no tomorrow.
我听到闻到的是什么
What is that I hear and smell?
马上就会被我送入地狱的人
Someone I'll soon send to hell.
是时候见证传言的真假了
It's time to see if truth they told
据说泰温·兰尼斯特能拉出黄金
who said Tywin Lannister shits gold.
你这个禽兽  禽兽
You beast. You beast.
你害死了我的妻子  现在又杀了自己的父亲
You killed my wife and now you've taken your father's life.
没有比你更大逆不道的儿子了
No worse child ever stained this land.
我诅咒为你命名的那一天
Curse the day I named you.
这是我最大的罪孽  现在我得跑了
My greatest crime. Now I must flee.
我要穿过狭海
Then sail across the Narrow Sea
背叛你到底
to do unto you more treachery.
不要畏惧寒冬  畏惧我吧
Don't fear winter. Fear me!
谢谢
Thank you.
女士们先生们  让我们感谢比安卡
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you Bianca,
克莱恩佐
Clarenzo.
感谢博邦奴
I give you Bobono.
和卡迈罗
I give you Camello.
最后  我们最出色的
And last but not least,
亲爱的克连恩夫人
sweet Lady Crane.
好好拍打  把跳蚤打出来  这可是宝贝
Give this a good beating. Shake those fleas out. That's a dear.
那些观众都是白痴
That crowd was shit.
丫头
Girl.
你在后台做什么
What are you doing back here?
没做什么
Nothing.
那天我在观众里见过你
I saw you the other day in the audience.
这出愚蠢的戏你看过几次了
How many times have you seen this stupid play?
三次
Three times.
你付过钱吗
Did you pay?
没有
No.
我记得那时候戏班子来我的村子演出
I remember when the players came to my village.
我身上一分钱都没有  就偷偷溜进去了
I didn't have any money, so I snuck in.
跟你现在一样
Just like you.
看着上了妆的脸蛋  戏服
Saw the painted faces, the costumes,
听着他们唱歌
listened to the songs,
在年轻的恋人死在对方怀里时放声大哭
cried when the young lovers died in each other's arms.
第二天我就逃离村子加入了他们
I ran off and joined them the next day,
再也没回头
never looked back.
你演得真好
You're very good.
我最后的几句台词糟透了
My final speech is shit.
但是公平地说  我总喜欢这么告诉自己
But to be fair to myself, which I always like to be,
是剧本写得不怎么样
the writing's no good.
那就改写
So change it.
这出戏如果没有你
It would all just be farting, belching,
就只剩下放屁打嗝扇耳光了
and slapping without you.
你会怎样改写剧本
How would you change it?
王后爱他的儿子  胜过世上的一切
The queen loves her son more than anything.
但她连道别的机会都没有  他就死掉了
And he was taken from her before she could say good-bye.
她不应该只是哭
She wouldn't just cry.
她应该愤怒
She would be angry.
她渴望杀死那个令她伤心的人
She would want to kill the person who did this to her.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
茉慈
Mercy.
你的眼睛会说话  茉慈
You have very expressive eyes, Mercy.
眉毛也漂亮
Wonderful eyebrows.
你喜欢扮演角色吗
Do you like pretending to be other people?
我得走了  我父亲在等着我呢
I have to go. My father's waiting for me.
克连恩夫人  观众们爱死你了
Lady Crane, they loved you.
他们太热情了  或者醉得厉害
They were sweet. Or drunk.
热情到醉
Drunkenly sweet.
奈德死的那一幕没人笑
No laugh for Ned's death.
这群观众猪狗不如
These people are worse than animals.
但是他们爱她  他们都爱她
But they loved her. They all love her.
没错  崇拜你的是猪狗不如的观众
Yes, you are adored by people and animals alike.
我尽量在这种基础上发挥
I do what I can with what I'm given.
哪种基础
With what you're given?
我只是在思考...
Well, I was thinking--
我们现在都是思考者了吗
Oh, we're all thinkers now, are we?
大奶子里全是想法
Full to the tits with ideas.
-我不是说...  -你有想法  我有想法
- I didn't mean-- - You have ideas, I have ideas,
他也有想法
he has ideas.
我的想法为什么比你们的更有价值
Why should my ideas have any more value than yours
就是因为我这辈子都在干这一行吗
simply because I've been doing this my whole life?
谁有资格来评判我的作品
Who is anyone to judge my work?
这是我的专业  我知道自己在做什么
This is my profession. I know what I'm doing.
你没有权利发表意见
You have no right to an opinion.
小心那个人
Careful of that one.
她想要你死
She wants you dead.
怎么样
And?
跟我预想的一样
As I expected.
真遗憾
A shame.
女孩天份不错
A girl had many gifts.
你答应过我
You promised me.
别让她受罪
Don't let her suffer.
全体停止前进
Company, halt!
队长大人
My lord.
提利尔大人
朋友们  这个时刻到了
My friends, the hour has come.
疯狂已经控制了这座城市
Madness has overtaken this city
我的孩子们身陷魔爪
and grasped in its claws my children.
但是现在  我们必须将其
But now we must drive it back
打回石头缝里的老家
under the rocks whence it came.
疯狂的末日已至
Madness has had its day!
全体前进
Forward, march!
不管富人还是穷人  贵族还是平民
Rich or poor, noble or common,
如果我们有罪  就必须赎罪
if we sin, we must atone.
提利尔家族的玛格丽
Margaery of House Tyrell
以罪人的身份面对我们
came to us a sinner.
她站在大教堂里
She stood before the gods
在诸神面前撒谎
in the holy sept and lied.
她对自己哥哥的罪行视而不见
She turned a blind eye to her brother's sins.
她羞辱了自己的家族
She disgraced her house,
羞辱了她的国王  和她自己
her king, and herself.
全体停止前进
Company, halt!
向前看
Face front!
转身
Turn!
提利尔大人
Lord Tyrell.
詹姆爵士
Ser Jaime.
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to interrupt.
我们为玛格丽王后和洛拉斯·提利尔爵士而来
We're here for Queen Margaery and Ser Loras Tyrell.
把他们交出来我们就离开
Give them to us and we'll be on our way.
我无权把他们交给你
I don't have the authority to give them to you.
你也无权带走他们
And you don't have the authority to take them.
说得对
That's right.
驾
Hyah.
上矛
Lock spears!
我代表拜拉席恩家族的国王托曼一世
I speak for King Tommen of House Baratheon, First of His Name.
诸神在此事上不认可他的权威
The gods don't recognize his authority in this matter.
你已经侮辱了一个大家族
You've already insulted one great house.
不会再有第二次
It won't happen twice.
在玛格丽·提利尔上街之前
Every last sparrow will die
我们会杀死所有的麻雀
before Margaery Tyrell walks down that street.
为侍奉诸神而死
To die in the service of the gods
我们死得其所
would please each and every one of us.
我们求之不得
We yearn for it.
但今天不是时候
But there is no call for it today.
不会有赎罪之旅
There will be no walk of atonement.
收阵
Order up.
玛格丽王后已经通过将另一人
Queen Margaery has already atoned for her sins
引入七神的圣光之下
by bringing another
赎清了她的罪孽
into the true light of the Seven.
我们在此共同宣布
Together we announce
和谐的新时代开启
a new age of harmony.
王权与信仰
A holy alliance
神圣的联合
between the Crown and the Faith.
托曼国王万岁  诸神保佑您  玛格丽王后
Long live King Tommen and bless you, Queen Margaery!
王权与信仰
The Crown and the Faith
是这个世界赖以依存的两大支柱
are the twin pillars upon which the world rests.
我们将携手重筑七国的荣耀
Together we will restore the Seven Kingdoms to glory.
怎么回事
What's happening?
他打败了我们
He's beaten us.
就是这么回事
That's what's happening.
攻击信仰  就是攻击王权
When you attack the Faith, you attack the Crown.
任何攻击王权的人都不应当
Anyone who attacks the Crown is unfit
担任御林铁卫队长
to serve as Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
在你出生以前我就是御林铁卫的一员了
I've been a member of the Kingsguard since before you were born.
你不必这样做  你什么都不需要做
You don't have to do this. You don't have to do anything.
我必须听从诸神的指示
I have to answer to the gods.
在你还坐在王座上的时候就不需要
Not when you're sitting in that chair.
身为国王  我意已决
The Crown's decision on this matter is final.
我要裸体游街吗
Will I be walking naked in the streets?
还是先在圣堂地牢里待几个月
Or will I spend a few months in the Sept dungeons first
学学诸神是如何仁慈
to teach me about the gods' mercy?
你为你的家族
You have served your house
和国王效忠了多年
and your king faithfully for many years.
你也将继续如此
And you will continue to do so.
但不是在这个城市
But not in this city.
你搞丢了
You've lost it?
是的  父亲
Yes, Father.
那是城堡  又不是羊
It's a castle, not a bloody sheep.
你应该还知道它在哪儿
Presumably you still know where it is.
你没有搞丢奔流城
You didn't lose Riverrun.
你是让黑鱼夺走了它
You let the Blackfish take it from you.
他突袭了我们  他比任何人都更了解奔流城
He surprised us. He knows the castle better than anyone.
红色婚礼之后你倒是搞丢了黑鱼
You did lose the Blackfish after the Red Wedding.
他就在这个厅里  你却让他离开了
You had him right here in this hall and you let him leave.
然后当我要你去追捕并杀了他时
Then when I told you to hunt him down and kill him,
你找不到他了
you couldn't find him.
这才叫搞丢了
That's what it means to lose something.
现在他回来夺走了奔流城
Now he's come back and taken Riverrun.
我觉得不该怪我们...
I don't think it's fair to blame us--
我们匍匐在徒利家脚下长达三百年
For 300 years we kissed Tully boots,
向他们及其腥臭的鳟鱼旗宣誓效忠
swore oaths to them and their stinking fish banners.
再也不会了  奔流城是我们的
Not again. Riverrun is ours.
夺回来
Take it back.
我们没有人手
We don't have the men.
我们的人手十倍于该死的黑鱼
We've got 10 times as many men as the damn Blackfish.
梅利斯特家已与我们为敌  还有布莱伍德家
The Mallisters have risen against us. And the Blackwoods.
无旗兄弟会正在召集平民对付我们
The Brotherhood Without banners is rallying the commoners against us,
抢劫我们的供给车队和军营
raiding our supply trains and camps.
奔流城能在围城战中抵抗一年
Riverrun can withstand a siege for a year.
我如果找借口  就会让她管事
If I want excuses, I'll put her in charge.
他们在嘲笑我们
They're laughing at us.
从河间地
All across the Riverlands
到君临城
right down to King's Landing,
他们在嘲笑我们
they're laughing at us.
我睡觉也能听见
I hear it in my sleep!
不幸的是  我还没死
I'm not dead yet, unfortunately for you.
并且在他们笑得哽住之前
And I'll not leave this world
我不会离开这个世界
until they all choke on that laughter.
夺回城堡
Take that castle back.
他不会屈服的  父亲
He'll never yield, Father.
他会的
Oh, he'll yield.
你  给他看你捅进婊子的肚子
You'll show him the knife
杀了罗柏·史塔克孩子的那把刀
you used to kill Robb Stark's child in his whore mother's belly,
而你  给他看你割开
and you'll show him the knife
他侄女喉咙的那把刀
you used to open his niece's throat.
你们要提醒他
And you'll remind him
一开始在红色婚礼上结婚的是谁
who it was that got married at the Red Wedding in the first place.
他的侄子
His nephew.
高兴点  艾德慕大人
Cheer up, Lord Edmure.
你要回家了
You're going home.
我被派去对付黑鱼
I'm being sent to deal with the Blackfish.
显然瓦德·佛雷自己处理不了
Apparently Walder Frey can't manage it on his own
因为他已经四百岁了
because he's 400 years old.
让我带兵前往奔流城
Sent me with an army to the Riverlands
打一场能持续数月的围城战
and a siege that could last months.
无论你带兵去哪儿
Better you're elsewhere at the head of an army
都好过被关在圣堂的地牢
than in the sept dungeons.
我不去河间地
I'm not going to the Riverlands.
那怎么办
What, then?
我要给波隆金子  数不胜数的金子
I'm going to give Bronn the largest bag of gold anyone's ever seen
让他去召集最好的杀手
and have him gather the best killers he knows.
我带他们去大圣堂
I'll take them to the sept
我要摘下大麻雀的脑袋
and I'll remove the High Sparrow's head
还有我能找到的每一只麻雀的脑袋
and every other sparrow head I can find.
不行
You can't.
我们儿子在他手里  他抢了我们的儿子
He has our son! He stole our son!
他拆散了我们家
He's torn our family apart.
我们应该怎么对待拆散我们的人
How should we treat people who tear us apart?
我们应该毫不留情  我们也绝不会仁慈
We should treat them without mercy and we will.
可如果杀了大麻雀  你没法活着走出圣堂
But if you kill the High Sparrow, you won't leave the sept alive.
没了你  这一切都毫无意义
And without you, this is all for nothing.
统领我们的军队  那才是属于你的位置
Stand at the head of our army where you belong,
也是父亲对你的希望
where Father wanted you.
让我们的军队知道他们该效忠谁
Show our men where their loyalties belong.
让他们看看兰尼斯特的本事
Show them what Lannisters are,
我们对待敌人的手段
what we do to our enemies.
夺回那座愚蠢的小城堡
And take that stupid little castle back
因为它本就属于我们  因为你有这个能力
because it's ours and because you can.
你即将面临审判  我要留下来陪你
You'll stand trial soon. I need to be here for you.
那是比武审判
It will be a trial by combat.
我有魔山
I have the Mountain.
他们让我们更强大  我们所有人
They've made us both stronger, all of them.
他们不知道我们有多强
They have no idea how strong we are.
不知道我们准备如何对付他们
No idea what we're going to do to them.
我们一直在一起
We've always been together.
以后也会一直在一起
We'll always be together.
这世上只剩我们两个了
We're the only two people in the world.
为什么救我们
Why did you help us?
三眼乌鸦派我来的
The Three-Eyed Raven sent for me.
三眼乌鸦死了
The Three-Eyed Raven's dead.
现在他又活了
Now he lives again.
上次见你  你还是个小孩
When I last saw you, you were a boy.
无所畏惧
A fearless boy.
喜欢爬城墙  让他母亲担心坏了
Loved to climb the castle walls, frighten his mother.
你是谁
Who are you?
班扬叔叔
Uncle Benjen.
琼恩写来的最后一封信上说
The last letter Jon wrote me
你在长城外失踪了
said you had been lost beyond the Wall.
我带着游骑兵深入北边
I led a ranging party deep into the North
去寻找异鬼
to find white walkers.
他们找到了我们
They found us.
其中一个异鬼用一把冰剑刺中了我的肚子
A white walker stabbed me in the gut with a sword of ice.
留下我等死
Left me there to die.
转变
To turn.
森林之子找到了我
The Children found me.
驱散了异鬼对我的魔法控制
Stopped the walker's magic from taking hold.
怎么做的
How?
就是他们最初制造异鬼的办法
The same way they made the walkers in the first place.
你亲眼看过
You saw it yourself.
龙晶
Dragonglass.
一片龙晶刺进你的心脏
A shard of dragonglass plunged into your heart.
你现在是三眼乌鸦了
You are the Three-Eyed Raven now.
我没有足够的时间学习  我无法控制一切
I didn't have time to learn. I can't control anything.
你必须学会控制
You must learn to control it
趁着夜王还没有来
before the Night King comes.
喝
Drink.
不管怎样
One way or another,
他终会找到通向人类世界的路
he will find his way to the world of men.
等他找到
When he does,
你会在那里等他
you will be there waiting for him.
你会做好准备
And you will be ready.
没事吧
Everything all right?
骑回弥林需要多久
How many days' ride to Meereen?
最多一周
A week at best.
需要多少船才能载我的卡拉萨去维斯特洛
How many ships will I need to bring my khalasar to Westeros?
多斯拉克人和他们的马
Dothraki and all their horses,
无垢者和次子团
the Unsullied, the Second Sons--
估计一千艘船
1,000 ships easily.
-可能还不够  -谁有这么多
- Probably more. - And who has that many?
没人有
Nobody.
目前没人有
Nobody yet.
这么说我们骑马回了弥林
So we ride for Meereen
之后就乘船去维斯特洛
and after that we sail for Westeros.
然后呢
And what then?
我要夺回属于我的一切
I take what is mine.
您生来就不是坐在王宫椅子上的人
You weren't made to sit on a chair in a palace.
那我生来是什么人
What was I made for?
您是征服者  风暴降生丹妮莉丝
You're a conqueror, Daenerys Stormborn.
等着
Wait here.
我随她去
在这里等我
过去每位卡奥都会选出三名血盟卫
与他并肩作战  保护他免于危难
但我不是卡奥
我也不选三位
我选你们全部
我的要求也比
任何卡奥对卡拉萨的要求都多
你们愿意骑着木马横渡黑色咸水吗
你们愿意杀死穿铁衣服的人
拆了他们的石头房子吗
你们愿为我打下七大王国吗
这是卓戈卡奥曾许诺我的礼物
他在圣母山前向我发誓
你们愿跟随我吗
从现在起
直到永远
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第六季 第六集
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Silmar 草草 潇湘月影
翻译：盐湖凉开水 煮粥达人 泰斯
校对：泰斯·雪诺 Silmar   顾问：屈畅(ccxx)
时间轴：崽猪 加森 Avis aaaBao
后期：吉吉·波顿  总监：泰斯·雪诺
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
手机APP搜索
人人影视字幕组
官方APP
更新下载手机搞定
讨论交流登陆升级
到各大市场搜索
"人人影视字幕组"
下载网址：app.zimuzu.tv